Bennett Adams

UI/UX Designer

Frontend Developer

bennettadams@hotmail.com

bennettadams.net

As a designer that also likes to write frontend code my experience gives me a unique perspective and skillset. I balance aesthetics with usability to create ideal user experiences, testing them as often as possible with real users, and then bring them to life in the browser using the latest frontend technologies.

Skills		Certifications
7+ years	Frontend Development	NN/g UX Basic Training
	HTML, CSS & Sass, JS, React, Angular, Git, NPM	Aug. 2019
5+ years	UI/UX Design	AWS Technical Professional Accreditation
	User research, User flow diagrams, IA, Wireframes,	Jan. 2019
	Prototypes	AWS Business Professional Accreditation
7+ years	Visual Design	Feb. 2019
	Logo Design, Branding, Graphic Design, Illustrations	

Experience

JUL. 2017 - PRESENT

UX Engineer at Element 84

- Designing, prototyping, and ultimately helping build the UI for a React-powered search engine for Oceanographers.
- Complete rebuild and redesign of a website (and CMS) for a prominent Earth Science Data Center affiliated with NASA
- Designing and building the Angular UI for a prominent medical university's biobanking app.
- Redesign and implementation of element84.com using React/Gatsby frontend, WP-API for CMS, Design System for consistency and maintainability.

DEC. 2012 - JUL. 2017

UI/UX Designer at SPARGO, Inc.

Designed and helped to implement a standardized but customizable template used across the 80+ different clients that all required different branding for their Event Registration and Housing websites. On an average day I used Photoshop and/or code to create hi-fidelity mockups and prototypes to pitch to stakeholders. In addition to client work I also helped to re-brand the company from J. Spargo & Associates to SPARGO, including designing the logo, business cards, corporate style guide.

DEC. 2012 - PRESENT

Freelance Designer & Developer

Early in my career, especially when transitioning from a junior "Web Designer" to a UI/UX Designer, I tried to build a portfolio by finding work through friends and family and through sites like Upwork. Projects included...

- Designing UI screens for an on-demand services app in Sketch
- Designing and building a launch page and sign-up form for a new medical app.
- Re-designing and fixing bugs in an existing Wordpress site for a band

Education

Osbourn Park High School

Advanced Degree

2000 - 2004

Radford University
B.S. in Information

Systems & Sciences

2005 - 2009